Yury Talapila

Senior Software Engineer

yury.talapila@gmail.com Kraków, Poland https://www.linkedin.com/in/yury-talapila-2302764a/ https://github.com/kreasl

Education

Belarusian State University, Minsk, Belarus

Applied Mathematics

Professional Summary

Seasoned software engineer with 17 years of experience in developing API, services, infrastructure and full-cycle web-apps. Including 10 years of JavaScript / TypeScript development

Skills

JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, PHP

Nest.js, Express.js, Next.js, React

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Prisma ORM, DynamoDB, Firebase, Gremlin

CloudFront, EKS, RDS, DynamoDB, CloudFormation, API Gateway, Lambda, S3, EC2

Kafka, RabbitMQ, Bull Queue

Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Serverles, GitHub actions

API, SaaS integrations, message queues, data pipelines, DI/DX, microservices, DDD RnD, Team leadership, Agile facilitation, BA, diagramming, technical documentation Code review, pair programming, mentorship OOP, FP, SOLID, GRASP

Professional Experience

NDA — May 2024 - Now

Software Engineer

Prototyping, Architecture design, API design, RnD

Node.js, Typescript, Express.js, Nest.js, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, CloudFront, Terraform, LangGraph

SportsBroker (Betting) — May 2022 - May 2024, Kraków

Software Developer - Backend

Development, maintenance, architecture design, RnD, data pipelines design, data analysis, microservices design, SaaS integrations, release management, team facilitation

Node.js, Typescript, Express.js, Nest.js, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, DynamoDB, Firebase, Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, S3, Miro, Raycast

- Developed and maintained API platform
- Maintained data pipeline
- Developed and maintained a number of data migration and extraction scripts
- Designed and implemented integration of external: marketing platforms; data provider; identity verification service, authentication service and payment service
- Refactored payment module
- Designed, implemented and maintained Marketing module, consisting of several microservices that synchronize data between internal DBs and several external platforms
- Maintained codebase, keeping it up to date and introducing code quality tools and workflows
- Supported Marketing, Customer Support and Compliance teams, when they needed data analysis
- In a crisis situation on production in Team Lead absence assumed leadership role. Performed investigation of the problem cause, which resulted in immediate temporary solution. Planned and facilitated the long term solution for the underlying issue
- Updated and helped to maintain CI/CD pipelines

Carrier (IoT fleet management app), Klika Tech — May 2021 - Jan 2022, Minsk

Software Developer - Full Stack

Development, Agile facilitation

Node.js, TypeScript, AWS, CloudFormation, Serverless, React, Nx

• Maintained an AWS-based IoT fleet management solution

Arago (Al-enabled IT infrastructure management app), Klika Tech — Sep 2019 - Jan 2022, Minsk

Software Developer - Frontend

Development, BA, feature design, front-ops, test automation, Scrum facilitation JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Storybook, Gremlin Graph DB, Cypress, Miro

- Developed and maintained several React apps
- Proposed, designed and facilitated Components Library approach to multiple React apps
- Facilitated Scrum processes

Tulip (Retail CRM / E-commerce suite), Klika Tech — May 2016 - Sep 2019, Minsk

Software Developer - Full Stack, Team Lead

Development, architecture design, test automation design, BA, team leadership, mentoring

Node.js, JavaScript, PHP, Ruby, MySQL, Codecept.js, Appium, Express.js, React, Symfony, CodeIgniter, Docker, Apache, Nginx, AWS, Miro

- Developed and maintained React and PHP applications
- Lead a full-cycle React app development. Started as a developer and had been promoted as a Lead of a team of 18
- Designed and lead a solution to use the React app as a micro-frontends container and management tool
- Lead a team of 6 QA engineers to create an e2e tests suite and integrated it into company's CI/CD pipelines and projects' workflow

Feedgi (Social media feed control panel) — May 2015 - May 2016, Remote

Software Developer - Full Stack

BA, project management, architecture design, development JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Angular, Bootstrap, Docker, Git

- Developed a web-crawling / content sharing / publishing solution
- Designed and implemented a core module
- Added import integrations for Facebook, Blogspot and Twitter
- Added publishing integrations for Facebook, Blogspot, Twitter and email
- Created a customer and administrator control panels

Politico (Publishing tool), Epam — Sep 2014 - Apr 2015, Minsk

Software Engineer - Full Stack

Development

PHP, JavaScript, Angular, Vagrant, Ansible

• Maintained a publishing solution

TMC (Internal training and education portal), Epam — Jun 2013 - Sep 2014, Minsk

Software Engineer - Full Stack

Development, SaaS integration

PHP, JavaScript, Zend Framework 2, Symfony 2, Backbone, Vagrant, Ansible

• Developed an internal learning platform

WorldAdCom (Professional social network), Intetics — Nov 2012 - Jun 2013, Minsk

Senior Software Engineer - Full Stack

Development

PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, MS SQL, Zend Framework, Backbone.js

• Developed and maintained social network prototype

SugarCRM, Intetics — May 2012 - Feb 2013, Minsk

Senior Software Engineer - Full Stack

Development

JavaScript, PHP, MySQL

Maintained a CRM core

ShowMe (Packages & release management tool), HTC Bel — Aug 2010 - May 2012, Minsk

Senior Software Engineer - Full Stack

Development

JavaScript, PHP, MySQL

- Designed and developed a packages publishing tool

Languages

Russian, Belarusian — native

English-C1

Polish — B1

German — A1